So you want to be a teaching artist?
That's awesome.
A teaching artist is basically
just a practicing artist
who teaches.
The trick is that a lot of people in society
think you can just throw
an artist
in the classroom, and they can just kinda teach.
Artists are amazing, artists can do anything.
But having some training and skills
like classroom management, lesson planning,
things like that,
can really go a long way
in terms of successful experiences
for you and your future students.
There are a lot of training
programs out there,
some of which are associated
with non-profits
who then hire teaching artists
and will then place you in schools,
museums, community centers.
It might be one-off workshops
or longer-term residencies
in the classroom,
after school.
The sky is really the limit
in terms of what teaching artists can do.
It's very helpful
to have some arts
integration training
so that you can connect the arts
with other academic subjects,
and it's really helpful
to have social emotional
learning training
so that your arts teaching
can enrich the whole person.
It's also important to remember
that being a teaching artist
is often freelance gig work.
You might even start
your own little business,
and even if you don't,
you still really need
to market your services
and to know what sets
your teaching artistry apart
because it becomes the product.
I love being a teaching artist
because it's very independent,
very dynamic.
You can go from project
to project, do multiple jobs
at the same time, take breaks
to focus on your own artwork.
But you have to know
that's the lifestyle
you're signing up for.
If this sounds like you,
check out some of the training programs
so that you can get started
acquiring the tools and skills that you’ll need
to enter the exciting world of teaching artistry.